Bohdan Mykytey

Stamford, CT. 06905 | (203) 921-6809 | bohdan.mykytey@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/bohdanmykytey/

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER | AUTOMATIONS ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

My expertise lies in user interfaces and automation. My contributions to the Dow Jones Suite of Software saw a 20% uplift in user retention globally, across the Wall Street Journal, Barron's and Market Watch Platforms. This resulted in Hundreds of Thousands of users dissuaded from canceling their subscriptions, massively driving the annual bottom line.

Areas of expertise include:

UI Expert

• Agile/Scrum

Project Lead Experience

• JS, Python, Ruby Certified

• User Retention

• Node, CI/CD, Optimizely

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, C#, React, Redux, Node.JS

Applications: VS Code, Optimizely, NODE-RED, ARGO, Jenkins CI, PyCharm, AWS Console and Server Maintenance,

Kubernetes CL.

Infrastructure: Windows, Mac, Linux (Ubuntu), AWS, Kubernetes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dow Jones, New York, NY

April 2022 - June 2024

User Retention – Full Stack Software Developer

My most recent role was at Dow Jones, where I was responsible for building custom user interfaces. Leveraging imperative my programming skills using Vanilla JavaScript, HTML and CSS I built out user interface experiments, where we tested a variety of custom UIs to see which one would retain the largest number of subscribers.

- The scrum process consisted of the following:
 - Ideate and come up with a hypothesis
 - Gather business and other stakeholder requirements
 - o Build out UI Version A, B, C, D etc. using "Ethical Hacking", taking over the DOM and UI without the customer ever knowing.
 - o Track user Metrics and KPI's with Optimizely
 - Intergrade the best performing UI into the broad world of Dow Jones applications including WSJ,
 Barron's and Market Watch. My job included rewriting Vanilla JavaScript into modern React Hooks for seamless integration with the established API's and CI/CD pipelines.
- My most proud accomplishment with Dow Jones was that my work saw a **20% uplift** in user retention. I was the sole developer on this piece of the application. It makes me humble and proud to think that I was responsible for that much of an impact to the annual bottom line.

General Assembly, Remote

May 2022 - Aug 2022

Lead Software Engineering Instructor

My role as a Lead Instructor was to educate adult students who have never touched code before and giving them a solid foundation in OOP and Functional Programming – taking them from complete beginners to Full Stack Developers over the course of the Full Stack Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp.

My biggest accomplishment at General Assembly was the personalized thank you messages on slack I would get
from students after a lesson. Finding ways to break down complex OOP and Functional programming concepts into
easy to digest every day examples were my biggest strength. This brought me the most self-fulfillment – knowing

Bohdan Mykytey

that I am making an impact and helping someone who is having a hard time grasping these complex ideas and concepts.

• Responsibilities included lesson planning, teaching topics, creating labs, creating and assigning homework and leading the 2-hour long lectures focusing on dialog and a Q&A type of learning environment where the students felt encouraged to learn and grow.

Axcess Financial, Cincinnati, OH

April 2020 - March 2022

Full Stack Developer, Automations Engineer

My role at Axcess Financial consisted of building custom full stack applications for internal use and writing automation code to test API's and User Interfaces.

- Built internal applications for all relevant stake holders using:
 - o React, React Hooks, Formik, Redux, C# Core API, SQL, Node, Express JS.
- Built dozens of various automations to test API's and User Interfaces using, JavaScript, NODE-RED, Python and Selenium.
- My Automations and Custom Applications were hosted on my own AWS C3 instances. I built and maintained the
 entire CI/CD pipeline to ensure continuous platform availability with no outages. The biggest lesson learned in this
 role was extensive unit testing of my own code in Q/A to be 100% certain that it would work flawlessly in
 production.

General Assembly, Stamford, CT

June 2019 – September 2019

Full Stack Software Engineering Student/Fellowship

Built fluency in full-stack web development through completing an intensive three-month program focused on common best practices in in software development.

• Learned OOP and Functional programming from a beginner's perspective, eventually graduating with a deep knowledge of modern programming languages and software engineering concepts such as JavaScript and Python, HTML, CSS, React, Mongo DB, Express, Node, Inheritance, Encapsulation, Code Reusability, API Development etc.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Stamford, CT

June 2019 – September 2019

Certificate of Graduation Attained

Housatonic College 2016 - 2018

Associate's degree, Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Udemy Perpetual

Continued Self Education

Solo Learn 2021- 2022

Advanced JavaScript Certification

Ruby Certification

Advanced Python Certification